Guide to the Brochsteins Inc. Corporate Records MS 717
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Brochsteins Inc. corporate records
1935-2000
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Brochsteins, Inc. (1935-)
MS 717
29 Linear Feet 19 archival boxes, 14 map drawers
Brochsteins Inc. corporate records contains architectural drawings, images, and business records from 1935-2000.
Historical Note
Brochsteins, Inc. of Houston has been a manufacturer of fine architectural woodwork and custom furniture since 1935. The company has provided widely diverse architecturally designed fixtures, such as paneling, doors, trim, desks, workstations and conference tables for financial institutions, law and corporate offices, public buildings, retail-commercial projects, as well as museums and residences. Each project is uniquely produced for each client, constructed according to the specifications of the architects and designers and coordinated according to the requirements of the contrator. Brochsteins develops detail drawings, mock-ups and prototypes, and provides assistance in the selection of woods for any project.
Scope and Contents
Brochsteins Inc. corporate records contains architectural drawings, images, and business records from 1935-2000.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Collection was donated by Deborah Brochstein, Brochsteins Inc. on Oct. 10, 2017.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged in three series: Series I Architectural drawings; Series II Images, Series III Business files, with subseries as necessary.
Index Terms
Subjects
Architecture; Architecture -- Texas -- Houston -- 20th century; Business
Document Types
architectural drawings (visual works); photographs
- Series I: Architectural drawings
  - Various; Braniff, International (Houston, TX); Brochstein's, Inc. plant and offices (Houston, TX); Amon Carter Museum (Ft. Worth, TX) (Drawer 198)
  - I.S. Brochstein residence (Houston, TX) (Drawer 199)
  - Economic Summit tables for Rice University (Houston, TX); Jake Freedman residence (Houston, TX); Hall jewelry store (Ft. Worth, TX); Kreeger residence (Washington, DC) (Drawer 200)
  - LTV Center (Dallas, TX); Marie Antoinette (Austin, TX) (Drawer 201)
  - Nations Bank (Charlotte, NC) (Drawer 202-203)
  - Reliant Energy 4th floor expansion (Houston, TX); Sakowitz (Houston, TX and Scottsdale, AZ) (Drawer 204)
  - Samsung, Inc. (Seoul, S. Korea) (Drawer 205)
  - Jos. Schlitz Brewing Co. (Memphis, TN); Shamrock Hotel (Houston, TX) (Drawer 206)
  - Shamrock Hotel (Houston, TX) (Drawer 207)
  - Shamrock Hotel (Houston, TX); Texas State Capitol (Austin, TX) (Drawer 208)
  - Texas State Capitol (Austin, TX) (Drawer 209-211)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals (Denver, CO); University of Houston (Houston, TX); Winstead, Sechrest and Minick (Houston, TX) (Drawer 212)
- Series II: Images
  - Sub-series A: Photographs: offices, retail, spaces
    - Dr. Alexander, Houston, TX (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American General, Houston, TX (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Amsouth, Birmingham, AL (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Amsouth, Riverchase (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Architectural Woodwork Corporation (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - J. Aron and Company (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Baker Botts, Dallas, TX (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Baker Botts, Washington, DC (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Becker's Fine Jewelry, Houston, TX, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bracewell & Patterson (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Capital National Bank, 3 Allen Center, Houston, TX (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Conoco (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Duke Energy (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Enron Corporate Headquarters, Houston, TX (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Esther Wolff (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Fashion Square, Houston, TX, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - First Baptist Church, Jackson, MS (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Fulbright and Jaworski, Houston, TX (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - GTE, Dallas, TX (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - General Dynamics, Washington, DC (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Getty Center, Los Angeles, CA (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Goldring's, New Orleans, LA, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Goldring's, Shreveport, LA, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Great Southern Life Insurance, Houston, TX (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Greenfield's, St. Louis, MO, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Gus Mayer, New Orleans, LA, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Hermes of Paris, Frost Bros., North Star Mall, San Antonio, TX (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Hess Corporation (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Houston Endowment, Houston, TX (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Houston I.S.D., Houston, TX (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Houston Livestock Show and Rodeo, Houston, TX (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Howery and Simon, Washington, DC (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Hutchins Bros., Houston, TX [oversize], 1949 (Box 3)
    - JDRP, Washington, DC (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Jones Day (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Julius Lewis, Memphis, TN, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - K and L, Pittsburgh, PA (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Kellogg (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Laufman's, Fashion Square (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Leon Gordon Jewelry, Houston, TX, 1938, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Lichtenstein's, Corpus Christi, TX, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Middle South conference room, New Orleans, LA (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mobil Oil Corp. headquarters, Fairfax, VA (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Muse 630 Shop, Atlanta, GA, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Muse Downtown, Atlanta, GA, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Neiman Marcus, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Neugebauer, Naples, FL (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Paul's Shoes, Dallas, TX, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Paul's Shoes, Houston, TX, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Reliant Energy lobby, Houston, TX (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Sakowitz Fabric Shop (4th floor), Houston, TX [oversize] (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz fine jewelry (1st floor), Houston, TX [oversize] (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz millinery French salon (3rd floor), Houston, TX [oversize] (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz men's (1st floor), Houston, TX [oversize] (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz men's shoes (1st floor), Houston, TX [oversize] (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz students (2nd floor), Houston, TX [oversize] (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz downtown, Houston, TX [oversize], 1951 (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz downtown (1st floor) [oversize], 1951 (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz downtown Red Coach Room (2nd floor), Houston, TX (2 views) [oversize], 1951 (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz downtown Van Dey woman's shoes (4th floor), Houston, TX [oversize], 1951 (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz downtown Young Houstonian, Houston, TX (2 views) [oversize] (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz downtown children's shoes (2nd floor), Houston, TX (2 views) [oversize] (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz downtown men's spectator sportswear (2nd floor), Houston, TX [oversize] (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz downtown Coronet Shop (4th floor), Houston, TX [oversize], 1951 (Box 3)
    - Sakowitz downtown women's sportswear (4th floor), Houston, TX [oversize], 1951 (Box 3)
    - Samsung (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Shamrock Hotel Smart Shop, Houston, TX (14 views) [oversize], 1949 (Box 3)
    - Shamrock Hotel Cork Club [b&w] [oversize], 1949 (Box 3)
    - Shamrock Hotel Emerald Room [b&w] [oversize], 1949 (Box 3)
    - Shamrock Hotel entrance [b&w] (2 views) [oversize], 1949 (Box 3)
    - Shamrock Hotel lobby and desk [b&w] [oversize], 1949 (Box 3)
    - Shamrock Hotel Pine Grill [b&w] (2 views) [oversize], 1949 (Box 3)
    - Shamrock Hotel Shamrock Room [b&w] [oversize], 1949 (Box 3)
    - Shaw's, Ft. Worth, TX (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Smart Shop downtown, Houston, TX, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Soleris, Fashion Square (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Sterling Chemicals, Houston, TX (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Sun Bank, Orlando, FL (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - UBS Investment Bank (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - USAA, San Antonio, TX (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - U.S. Court of Appeals, Denver, CO (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Vinson and Elkins prototype office (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Vinson and Elkins, Washington, DC (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Volk's, Dallas, TX, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Volk's Wynnewood, Dallas, TX, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Western Savings (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Wexner Bros. Smart Shop, Houston, TX (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Wynnewood State Bank, Dallas, TX (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified projects (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sub-series B: Photographs: General
    - Unidentified office complex (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Brochstein's office/factory complex (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Brochestein's office/factory complex construction [oversize], 1940 (Box 5)
    - Brochstein's office/factory complex [oversize], 1956 (Box 5)
    - Brochstein's office/factory complex [oversize], 1979 (Box 5)
    - Brochstein's office/factory complex [oversize], 1989 (Box 5)
    - Brochstein's office/factory complex [oversize], 1990s (Box 5)
    - I.S. Brochstein portrait (Map-drawer 198)
    - Brochstein's employee group, 1945-1949 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Brochstein's employee group, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Brochstein's employee group, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 8, Box 5)
    - Brochstein's employee group, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Brochstein's factory interior, 1940s (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Brochstein's factory interior, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Brochstein's factory interior, 2000s (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Brochstein's factory interior, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Brochstein's office interior, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Sapele logs (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Wood carvings (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Store fixtures (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Custom furniture (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Custom furniture: Desks (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Custom furniture: Sally Walsh desk for Braniff International, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Custom furniture: Sally Walsh desk chair, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Custom furniture: Sally Walsh sofa for Braniff International, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Custom furniture: Table for Economic Summit held at Rice University, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Negatives: unidentified [oversize] (Box 5)
  - Sub-series C: Negatives
    - Bailey Banks and Biddle (Box 6, Envelope 1)
    - Bauer-McCann, Waco, TX (Box 6, Envelope 2)
    - Becker's Fine Jewelry, Houston, TX [glass plate], 1936 (Box 7, Envelope 12)
    - Brochstein's, Houston, TX, 1940s (Box 6, Envelope 3)
    - Byrd's, Houston, TX [glass plates], 1935 (Box 7, Envelope 13-23)
    - Chimney Rock Bank, Houston, TX (Box 6, Envelope 4)
    - Coblenz (Box 6, Envelope 5)
    - Cowell and Hubbard (Box 6, Envelope 6)
    - Craig's Gulfgate, Houston, TX (Box 6, Envelope 7)
    - Craig's Village, Houston, TX, 1954 (Box 6, Envelope 8)
    - Crockett and Joseph, Fashion Square (Box 6, Envelope 9)
    - Crockett and Joseph beauty shop, Fashion Square (Box 6, Envelope 10)
    - D.H. Holmes (Box 6, Envelope 11)
    - Esther Wolff, Fashion Square (Box 6, Envelope 12)
    - Everitt Buelow, Houston, TX (Box 6, Envelope 13)
    - First Federal Bank, Little Rock, AR (Box 6, Envelope 14)
    - First National Bank, Edna, TX (Box 6, Envelope 15)
    - Godwin Shop, Corpus Christi, TX (Box 6, Envelope 16)
    - Goldring's, Baton Rouge and Lake Charles, LA (Box 6, Envelope 17)
    - Goldring's, New Orleans, LA (Box 6, Envelope 18-19)
    - Goldring's Airline, New Orleans, LA (Box 6, Envelope 20)
    - Goldring's, Shreveport, LA (Box 6, Envelope 21)
    - Goldstein-Wigel, Waco, TX (Box 6, Envelope 22)
    - Guaranty Bank and Trust Co., Alexandria, LA (Box 6, Envelope 23)
    - Gus Mayer, Baton Rouge, LA (Box 6, Envelope 24)
    - Gus Mayer, Carrollton, LA (Box 6, Envelope 25)
    - Gus Roos-Colbert's, Dallas, TX, 1955-02 (Box 6, Envelope 26)
    - Hanny's, Phoenix, AZ (Box 6, Envelope 27)
    - Hemphill-Wells, Lubbock, TX (Box 6, Envelope 28)
    - Hinkels, Albuquerque, NM (Box 6, Envelope 29)
    - Houston Bank and Trust (Box 6, Envelope 30)
    - Hub, Amarillo, TX (Box 6, Envelope 31)
    - Hutchins Bros., San Antonio, TX (Box 6, Envelope 32)
    - Julius Lewis, Memphis, TN (Box 6, Envelope 33)
    - Konner's (Box 6, Envelope 34)
    - Kreeger's Lakeside, New Orleans, LA (Box 6, Envelope 35)
    - Krupp and Tuffley Shoes, Fashion Square (Box 6, Envelope 36)
    - Laufner Jewelry, Fashion Square (Box 6, Envelope 37)
    - Lecheuger's Jewelry, Houston, TX (Box 6, Envelope 38)
    - Levy's, Houston, TX, 1936 (Box 7, Envelope 24-27)
    - Levy's, Memphis, TN (Box 6, Envelope 39)
    - Levy's, Tucson, AZ (Box 6, Envelope 40)
    - Maison Blanche (Box 6, Envelope 41)
    - Muse's downtown, Atlanta, GA (Box 6, Envelope 42)
    - Muse's Lennox, Atlanta, GA (Box 6, Envelope 43)
    - Needlecraft, Fashion Square (Box 6, Envelope 44)
    - Phelp's, Shreveport, LA (Box 6, Envelope 45)
    - Riff's, Lake Charles, LA (Box 6, Envelope 46)
    - Riff's, Longview, TX (Box 6, Envelope 47)
    - Rosenschweig's, Phoenix, AZ (Box 6, Envelope 48)
    - Rosenthal's, Oklahoma City, OK (Box 6, Envelope 49)
    - Rosenthal's Penn Square, Oklahoma City, OK (Box 6, Envelope 50)
    - Rothchild's downtown, Oklahoma City, OK (Box 6, Envelope 51)
    - Rothchild's Penn Square, Oklahoma City, OK (Box 6, Envelope 52)
    - Rupley's (Box 6, Envelope 53)
    - Sakowitz East End, Houston, TX (Box 6, Envelope 54)
    - Sakowitz Gulfate, Houston, TX (Box 6, Envelope 55)
    - Sakowitz Post Oak, Houston, TX (Box 6, Envelope 56)
    - Sakowitz, New Orleans, LA (Box 6, Envelope 57)
    - Security Federal Savings, Alice, TX (Box 6, Envelope 58)
    - Selbero's and Shudde's (Box 6, Envelope 59)
    - Shaw's, Dallas, TX (Box 6, Envelope 60)
    - Sloan-Blabon, Inc. (Box 6, Envelope 61)
    - Smart Shop, Houston, TX [glass plates], 1937 (Box 7, Envelope 28-31)
    - Solari's (Box 6, Envelope 62)
    - Stromberg's, Albuquerque, NM (Box 6, Envelope 63)
    - Texas State Bank, Victoria, TX (Box 6, Envelope 64)
    - Victoria Bank and Trust Co., Victoria, TX (Box 6, Envelope 65)
    - Volk's Live Oak, Highland Village (Box 6, Envelope 66)
    - Office/plant complex aerial, 1938 [?] (Box 7, Envelope 1)
    - Office/plant complex, 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Office/plant complex aerial, 1948-03-29 (Box 7, Envelope 3)
    - Office/plant complex aerial, 1948-12-20 (Box 7, Envelope 4)
    - Office/plant complex aerial, 1948-1956 [?] (Box 7, Envelope 5)
    - Office/plant complex, after 1948 (Box 7, Envelope 6)
    - Office/plant complex, 1956-07-13 (Box 7, Envelope 7)
    - Office/plant complex aerial, 1960 (Box 7, Envelope 8)
    - Office/plant complex aerial, 1961-05-09 (Box 7, Envelope 9)
    - Office/plant complex, 1988 (Box 7, Envelope 10)
    - Office/plant complex, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Sub-series D: Albums
    - Banks (designed and/or fixtured by Brochstein's Inc.)
      - Moody National Bank, Galveston, TX; Amon Carter Museum, Ft. Worth, TX; Houston First Federal Savings and Loan, Houston, TX; Highlands State Bank, Highlands, TX; Main Bank, Houston, TX (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
      - South Main State Bank, Houston, TX; Wharton Bank and Trust Co., Wharton, TX; Farm and Home Savings and Loan Association, Houston, TX; Boosier Bank and Trust Co., Boosier City, LA; Fannin State Bank, Houston, TX; The Peoples Bank, Natchitoches, LA; Concordia Bank and Trust Co., Ferriday, LA; City National Bank, Houston, TX; First National Bank, Eagle Lake, TX; Wynnewood State Bank, Dallas, TX; Great Southern Life Building, Houston, TX (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Security Federal Savings Bank, Alice, TX; Robstown National Bank, Robstown, TX; First State Bank, San Diego, TX; Bryan Building and Loan, Bryan, TX; First Federal Savings and Loan, Lake Charles, LA; Jeff Davis Bank and Trust, Jennings, LA; Guaranty Bank and Trust, Alexander, LA; First Federal Savings and Loan, Little Rock, AR (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Omaha National Bank, Omaha, NE; Houston National Bank, Houston, TX (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - First National Bank, Memphis, TN (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Boosier State Bank and Trust Co., Boosier City, LA (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Chimney Rock National Bank, Houston, TX (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - City National Bank, Houston, TX (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Highlands State Bank, Highlands, TX (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Houston First Financial, Houston, TX (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Texas National Bank, Houston, TX (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Texas National Bank, Victoria, TX (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Astrodome (fixtured by Brochstein's Inc.), Houston, TX (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Retail (designed and/or fixtured by Brochstein's Inc.)
      - Bailey, Banks and Biddle, Cherry Hill, NJ; Granat Bros., San Francisco, CA; Granat Bros., San Mateo, CA; Granat Bros., Santa Clara, CA; Slavick Jewelry Co., Los Angeles, CA; Bailey, Banks and Biddle, Pittsburgh, PA (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Bluestein's, Port Arthur, TX (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Corrigan's, Houston, TX (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Craig's, Houston, TX (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Everitt-Buelow Post Oak, Houston, TX (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Godchaux, New Orleans, LA (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Goldrings, Shreveport, LA (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Good Housekeeping, Inc. of Texas (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Gus Mayer Carrollton, New Orleans, LA (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Gus Mayer Company, New Orleans, LA (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Gus Roos, Republic National Bank Bldg., Dallas, TX (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Henry's, Twin Lakes, Wichita, KS (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Julius Lewis, Memphis, TN (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - M. Lichtenstein and Sons, Corpus Christi, TX (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
      - Martin's Oxmoor, Louisville, KY (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Miller and Rhoades, Crabtree Shopping Center, Raleigh, NC (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Miller and Rhoades, Tanglewood Mall, Roanoke, VA (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Miller and Rhoades, Virginia Beach, VA (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Muse's, Atlanta, GA (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Nathan's, Galveston, TX (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Neiman-Marcus, Houston, TX and Bal Harbour, FL (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Rosenzweigs Jewelers, Fashion Square Shopping Center, Scottsdale, AZ (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Rothschild's, Penn Square and downtown, Oklahoma City, OK (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Rothschild's, Oklahoma City, OK and Kansas City, MO (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Sakowitz downtown, Houston, TX (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Sakowitz Post Oak, Houston, TX (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
      - Sakowitz, Camelview Plaza, Scottsdale, AZ (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Sakowitz Town and Country Village, Houston, TX (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Shaw's, San Antonio, TX (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Stifft's, Little Rock, AR (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Vogue, San Antonio, TX (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Volk, Dallas, TX (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Series III: Business files
  - Prospectus (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
  - Stock certificates, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Plot plan, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Floor plan, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Newsclips (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Advertising (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Tax assessment (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Accolades (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Cutting bills and requisitions for Sally Walsh prototype furniture (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Recommendations (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Patent search (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Schedule of jobs (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Job log, 1978-1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Bank account deposit books (Box 15, Envelope 4-5)
  - Weekly time log book, 1952-1956 (Box 15, Envelope 6)
  - Invoices, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Invoices, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Stationery, 1940s (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Stationery, prior to 1948 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Stationery, 1950s-1960s (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Stationery, 1950s-1963 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Stationery (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Stationery, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Stationery, version B, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Stationery, I.S. Brochstein, 1960s (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Stationery, Raymond Brochstein (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Psychrometric charts (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Manual: Benson Manufacturing Company (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Manual: Frigidaire specifications (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Manual: Timber Engineering Co., 1953 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - National Lumber Manufacturing Association, 1939, 1946, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Portfolio: Architectural Woodwork Corp. (Box 17, Folder 6-8)
  - Catalogue "B": Burge Manufacturing Co. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Projects
    - Brochstein's, Inc. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Brochstein's, Inc. metal shop machine templates (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - I.S. Brochstein residence (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
    - Craig's color scheme, Galveston, TX (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Jake Freedman club, Houston, TX (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Gibbs-Louis color scheme, Altamonte Springs, FL (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Jason's finish schedule, Billings, MT (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Sakowitz, Shamrock Hotel, Houston, TX (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Shamrock Hotel, Houston, TX (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - University of Houston, Houston, TX (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - University of Houston Ezekiel Cullen building, Houston, TX (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - U.S. Courts/Federal Bldg./Post Office (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Sakowitz Post Oak color scheme, 1st floor (Box 19, Envelope 1-2)
    - Sakowitz Post Oak color scheme, 2nd & 3rd floors (Box 19, Envelope 3-4)
    - Sakowitz Post Oak flooring and base specifications, 1969-10-17 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Sakowitz Post Oak color, carpet, fabric and finish boards (Box 19)
    - Drawings: Tables (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Drawings: Buffets (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Drawings: Jewelry unit sections (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "The Citizen Newspapers present The Shamrock, A New Superlative" (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Reel-to-reel film: "Woodworking Wonderland," print #1 (Box 19)